Wilton Historical Society Wilton Historical Information Collection
Wilton History Room, Wilton Historical Society
- 3. Miscellaneous (by topic)
  - Schools
    - Middlebrook School, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 252d)
    - Middlebrook School - Early schoolhouse, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 252c)
    - Middle schools, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 252b)
    - Miller School, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 253a)
    - Montessori School, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 253aa)
    - Nod Hill School, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 253b)
    - Nursery schools, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 253ca)
    - Our Lady of Fatima - School, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 253cb)
    - Parent-Teacher Association (PTA), undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 254c)
    - Post School, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 253d)
    - Private schools, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 254a)
    - Project Concern, 1974-1981 (Cabinet 4, Folder 254b)
    - Projection Techniques Experiment, 1940-1942 (Cabinet 4, Folder 247ba)
    - Regional High School Controversy, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 255a, 255b)
    - Regional school, Georgetown, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 255b)
    - School buses and bus route map, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 256)
    - School closings, 1979 (Cabinet 4, Folder 257a)
    - Schools - Building program (long range), 1958 (Cabinet 4, Folder 238b)
    - Schools - Building Utilization Reports, 1985-1989; Reports are for the years 1985, 1986, and 1989. (Cabinet 4, Folder 238c)
    - Schools - Miscellaneous, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 234a)
    - Silvermine School, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 257b)
    - Study of education in Wilton, circa 1960 (Cabinet 4, Folder 258a)
    - Teachers, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 258b)
    - Time capsules, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 258c)
    - Weston Military Institute, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 258d)
    - Whitlock Academy, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 259)
    - Wilton Academy, 1820-1855 (Cabinet 4, Folder 260)
    - Wilton Academy research notes, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 261)
    - Wilton Education Association, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 262)
    - Wilton High School, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 264)
    - Wilton Junior High School, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 266)
    - Wilton schools - Miscellaneous documents, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 268)
  - Veterans, wars, and civil defense
    - Civil Defense, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 291da)
    - Civil Defense - Survival Plan, 1959-1963 (Cabinet 4, Folder 291e)
    - Civil Defense Preparedness, 1959-1983; This is a League of Women Voters study. (Cabinet 4, Folder 291d)
    - Civil War, 1861-1864 (Cabinet 4, Folder 560, 561, 562)
    - Civil War, American History class assignment, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 564)
    - Civil War, Georgetown soldiers, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 563)
    - Douglas, Damon - Papers on Revolutionary War, undated; File 581e includes Tryon’s Raid: Maps of the Area. (Cabinet 4, Folder 581b, 581c, 581d, 581e, 581f)
    - French and Indian War, 1758-1759 (Cabinet 4, Folder 565)
    - French and Indian War - Wilton train band (militia), 1710-1737 (Cabinet 5, Folder 755a)
    - Militia, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 375)
    - Revolutionary War, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 579a)
    - Revolutionary War - Burning of Norwalk, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 571a)
    - Revolutionary War - Danbury Expedition, 1777 (Cabinet 4, Folder 572, 573)
    - Revolutionary War - King George III - Statue, undated-1776; File 577b includes notes by Carboni. File 577bc includes correspondence. See also PHO 881. (Cabinet 4, Folder 575, 576, 577a, 577b, 577bc)
    - Revolutionary War - Miscellaneous, 1775-1783 (Cabinet 4, Folder 570)
    - Revolutionary War - Miscellaneous, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 578)
    - Revolutionary War - Nod Hill Neighborhood Parade / Float of King George III statue, 1976 (Cabinet 4, Folder 577d)
    - Revolutionary War - Notes by Damon Douglas, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 571b)
    - Revolutionary War - Notes by Damon Douglas on Tories and loyalists, undated; See also WHI, Wilton Tories. (Cabinet 4, Folder 580b)
    - Revolutionary War - Redding loyalists, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 579b)
    - Revolutionary War - Reminiscences, undated (Cabinet 5, Folder 599a)
    - Revolutionary War - Society of Cincinnati, 1783-1967 (Cabinet 4, Folder 580a)
    - Revolutionary War - The Midnight Ride of Sybil Ludington - Statue, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 577c)
    - Revolutionary War - Tryon's Raid, undated; See also OH and MC. (Cabinet 4, Folder 581a)
    - Revolutionary War - Veterans, undated; See also Scrapbooks 11 and 12, newspaper clippings of wartime activities in Wilton. (Cabinet 5, Folder 599b)
    - Revolutionary War - Wilton pensioners, 1736-1938; Information covers 1736-1816 and 1934-1938. (Cabinet 5, Folder 582)
    - Revolutionary War - Wilton Tories, 1775-1781 (Cabinet 5, Folder 584)
    - True Tale of the Revolutionary War, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 580c)
    - Veterans job training, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 552aa)
    - Veterans Memorial Green Committee, 2009-2011 (Cabinet 4, Folder 552c)
    - Veterans Memorial Green, and other memorials, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 552b)
    - Vietnam War, undated (Cabinet 5, Folder 599c)
    - War memorials, undated; See also Scrapbook 40. (Cabinet 4, Folder 566)
    - Wars - Miscellaneous, undated; See also diaries, scrapbooks, and the War Records Card File for alphabetical lists of Wilton service men compiled by G. Evans Hubbard. (Cabinet 4, Folder 558)
    - Western Reserve of Connecticut, 1935 (Cabinet 5, Folder 680)
    - Wilton Defense Council bulletins, undated (Cabinet 5, Folder 672)
    - Wilton Defense Council correspondence, undated (Cabinet 5, Folder 673)
    - Wilton Defense Council meetings minutes, undated (Cabinet 5, Folder 674)
    - Wilton Veterans Committee, 1944-1946; See also Scrapbook 40. (Cabinet 4, Folder 552d)
    - Wilton War Records Committee, undated (Cabinet 5, Folder 675)
    - Women in War, undated (Cabinet 5, Folder 676)
    - World War One - Leslie Withnell - Diary, undated; Diary is typewritten. (Cabinet 5, Folder 610)
    - World War One - Miscellaneous, undated (Cabinet 5, Folder 600)
    - World War One - Woman’s Land Army, undated (Cabinet 5, Folder 615)
    - World War Two - Air raid courses and members, 1941-1942 (Cabinet 5, Folder 654)
    - World War Two - Air raid training guides, 1941-1942 (Cabinet 5, Folder 656)
    - World War Two - Airplane spotting, undated; See also PHO. (Cabinet 5, Folder 652)
    - World War Two - Awards, undated (Cabinet 5, Folder 656b)
    - World War Two - Civilian defense, undated (Cabinet 5, Folder 660)
    - World War Two - Miscellaneous, undated (Cabinet 5, Folder 650)
    - World War Two - Ration books, undated (Cabinet 5, Folder 665)
    - World War Two - Rationing and salvage, undated (Cabinet 5, Folder 666)
    - World War Two - Selective Service (Draft List), undated (Cabinet 5, Folder 668)
    - World War Two - War bonds and loans, undated (Cabinet 5, Folder 670)
    - World War Two - Wartime committees, undated (Cabinet 5, Folder 671)
    - World War Two - Wilton Bulletin supplement, 1992 (Cabinet 5, Folder 657)
  - Wilton history and publicity
    See also OH, and Slides.
    - "(A) History (Excerpts) of Wilton Village", undated (Cabinet 5, Folder 723)
    - "A Visit with the Lamberts in 1724", undated (Cabinet 5, Folder 712)
    - "If you're thinking of living in Wilton," New York Times, 1984-2000; Articles date to 1984, 1991, 1999, and 2000. (Cabinet 5, Folder 732a)
    - "Town Clerk's dog register offers glimpse of town at turn of century", 1966 (Cabinet 5, Folder 741)
    - "Wilton leadership looks at their community", 1969 (Cabinet 5, Folder 739)
    - "Wilton," Board of Realtors, 1975-1986 (Cabinet 5, Folder 738)
    - "Wilton: A firm hand on its present, a clear eye on its future", 1981 (Cabinet 5, Folder 735)
    - "Wilton: Neither village nor town, fortress nor sanctuary, ‘just home'", 1979 (Cabinet 5, Folder 737)
    - "Wilton: The impossible dream", 1973 (Cabinet 5, Folder 746)
    - “Heritage Day” reminiscences, 1982 (Cabinet 5, Folder 727a)
    - “In Wilton...growing pains and gains”, 2000 (Cabinet 5, Folder 732b)
    - “Life in Wilton”, 1996 (Cabinet 5, Folder 723b)
    - “Nod Hill Reminisces”, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 420c)
    - “Salute to Wilton,” Norwalk Hour, 1963 (Cabinet 5, Folder 733)
    - “Wilton a profile”, 1969 (Cabinet 5, Folder 748)
    - “Wilton Then,” photograph exhibit captions, undated (Cabinet 5, Folder 753b)
    - “Wilton: 200 years of home rule,” Westport Magazine, 2002 (Cabinet 5, Folder 734)
    - “Wilton: A glimpse in its past, a pause its present, a salute to its future,” Westport News, 1964 (Cabinet 5, Folder 736)
    - “Wilton: In the golden age of postcards”, 1997 (Cabinet 5, Folder 749b)
    - Adams, Charles - “Reminiscences”, undated; See also Book 974.69 Adams. (Cabinet 5, Folder 725b)
    - Boundaries and perambulation lines, undated (Cabinet 5, Folder 715a)
    - Captions to library’s old photograph exhibits, 1995-2002 (Cabinet 5, Folder 715b)
    - Carboni, Robert - History of Wilton talk for 3rd grade students, 1964 (Cabinet 5, Folder 721ab)
    - Card family members - “Reminiscences of Growing Up in Wilton”, undated (Cabinet 5, Folder 725d)
    - Chelminski, Rudolph - “Recollections of a Childhood Friend named Crow Crow”, undated (Cabinet 5, Folder 724ab)
    - Collier, Christopher - “Reminiscences of Growing Up in Wilton, 1938-48”, undated (Cabinet 5, Folder 725c)
    - Colonial history, undated (Cabinet 5, Folder 719)
    - Colonial History of Wilton (CHOW) curriculum guide, undated (Cabinet 5, Folder 716)
    - Davenport, Rev. John Gaylord - “Wilton” (a song), undated (Cabinet 5, Folder 729d)
    - Earle, Morris - Diary of Lockwood Ferris, undated; See also Diaries 2. (Cabinet 5, Folder 717)
    - General reminiscences of Wilton, undated (Cabinet 5, Folder 726a)
    - Harris, Robert - “Somewhat Abridged History of Wilton”, 2002 (Cabinet 5, Folder 729ca)
    - Historical overview, undated (Cabinet 5, Folder 718)
    - History, undated (Cabinet 5, Folder 720a, 721aa, 721aaa)
    - Hubbard, G. Evans - “Short History of Wilton”, undated (Cabinet 5, Folder 729c)
    - Hurd, History of Wilton in Fairfield County, with Biographical Sketches of Prominent Men & Pioneers (reprint; 1881)., undated (Cabinet 5, Folder 721c)
    - Incorporation, 1802 (Cabinet 5, Folder 723a)
    - Keeler, Samuel - "Casual Reminiscences of North Wilton (c.1863)”, undated (Cabinet 5, Folder 725a)
    - Little known facts, undated (Cabinet 5, Folder 723c)
    - Old tales by Helen Gregory, undated (Cabinet 5, Folder 724a)
    - Original Wilton Families, undated (Cabinet 5, Folder 724aa)
    - Reference list of Wilton history, undated (Cabinet 5, Folder 724c)
    - Review of News, 1953-1992; Content dates to the years 1953-1956, 1975, 1987, and 1992. (Cabinet 5, Folder 728)
    - Rounds, Stowell - "Wilton of tomorrow", undated (Cabinet 5, Folder 747)
    - Rounds, Stowell - History of Wilton, undated (Cabinet 5, Folder 721b)
    - Russell, Robert H. - "200 Years of Wilton News: Murder, Scandal and Humor", undated (Cabinet 5, Folder 711a)
    - Russell, Robert H. - 1962 Wilton High School Class Reunion talk, undated (Cabinet 5, Folder 711b)
    - Story of Wilton and Ridgefield, 1965 (Cabinet 5, Folder 730ab)
    - Student papers and questions, undated (Cabinet 5, Folder 730b)
    - Thompson, Ada Maud, 1883-1975 - Memoirs, undated (Cabinet 5, Folder 727b)
    - Timeline, undated; Timeline covers 1295-1899. (Cabinet 5, Folder 722)
    - Top dates in Wilton’s history, undated (Cabinet 5, Folder 730c)
    - Town profiles - Miscellaneous, undated (Cabinet 5, Folder 731a)
    - Town ratings from Connecticut Magazine, undated (Cabinet 5, Folder 731b)
    - Town Seal, winner of 1964 contest, See also MC N11-2. (Cabinet 5, Folder 742)
    - Tuttle, Mildred - “Tales of early days in North Wilton”, 1945 (Cabinet 5, Folder 740)
    - Wenderoth, Ida F. - "Wilton history”, undated (Cabinet 5, Folder 745a)
    - Wilton History Day information, undated (Cabinet 5, Folder 749a)
    - Wilton in 1802 (Cabinet 5, Folder 711)
    - Wilton in 1802, undated (Cabinet 5, Folder 745b)